JAMES WOLFE

THE BEST CODER



Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com (703)789-0919 Northern Virginia Website Portfolio







SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in programming and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment such as the AWS Cloud, web development, Linux, and computer technology troubleshooting.

SKILLS

- Microsoft Excel **AWS Cloud Services** Visual Studio Code **Computer Troubleshooting**
- lava SSH Linux HTML & CSS

PROJECTS

Website Financial Dashboard with Arrays GitHub Repository

- Devised an EC2 static website and implemented ApexCharts with Java arrays to create a financial dashboard.
- Utilized services such as, Visual Studio Code, AWS Cloud, WinSCP, and GitHub to develop the project while working in a several phases, completing the project in one month.

Static Website Portfolios GitHub Repository

- Coded four HTML, CSS, and Java-Script website templates by uploading the files to database and publishing services like S3, Azure Container, Surge, and GitHub Pages.
- Wrote custom domain for the website using Google Domains and configured a connection in the DNS records.

AWS Amplify Application Website GitHub Repository

Streamlined an AWS Amplify project and put my skills to work in Linux and the AWS CLI conceptualizing an idea to have aa application as a website.

Headless Media Center

Achieved assembling a media center using a Raspberry Pi 4 by mounting Volumio OS to the device, making a blue-tooth hotspot available for connection.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

Worked through AWS Cloud troubleshooting tickets involving unable to POST and vital updates by rebooting servers, utilizing Linux update commands, reseating hardware and CAT5/6 cables, and other troubleshooting techniques.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 - 01/2019

Served customers while multi-tasking food orders, drink and chip refills, and station clean-up in a fast-paced environment to provide the best customer service

Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

- Faced with pet nutritional and health related issues I asked questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve customer concern and did it effectively by utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.
- Volunteered with Homeward Trails, German Shepherd Rescue, and PetValu by feeding dogs and cats and cleaning cages.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner - 7BEZSG02PNEEQ83D

Agile Scrum Fundamentals - ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp - ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College 2016 — 2020

Worked on the fundamentals on computers and how they function, practice coding in Java, HTML, and CSS, and worked through mathematical problems involving algebraic and transcendental formulas.